[Bret] In late May of 1980,
May 23rd to be exact,
The Shining opened,
and I wanted to see it
as soon as possible.
[♪ "Moving in Stereo" playing]
I was obsessed
with Stephen King's
seminal book.
And it remains
one of the key novels
that made me wanna be a writer.
♪♪ Life's the same
I'm moving in stereo ♪
In fact, as soon as I was done
reading The Shining
for a third time,
I began writing my own novel,
which would ultimately become
Less Than Zero.
♪♪ You're shakin' like tremolo ♪
This would be the first time
I drove to Westwood to see
a movie without the gang,
and I felt incredibly adult
as I raced across Mulholland
on that Saturday morning
in my father's
black Mercedes 450 SL,
a two-door tank that was hardly
the sporty vehicle I longed for
as a teenager.
♪♪ It's so easy
To blow up your problems ♪
I remember,
and I don't know why,
that I was wearing
a fashionable new
Ralph Lauren shirt,
brown with a touch
of white-gray stripes
and Calvin Klein jeans
with Gucci loafers.
One ticket, please.
Three dollars.
Thank you.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
I sat in reverent silence
and stared at
the 70-millimeter screen.
Writing this now,
I can't believe I was left to
my own devices for 20 minutes,
just idly sitting there,
thinking about things,
about my friends
Thom and Susan,
waiting without wanting
something to distract me
like smartphones
or social media.
The lights in the theater
slowly darken,
and that's when I saw the boy.
This is the reason why
I've never forgotten
seeing The Shining
on May 24th, 1980,
at the theater in Westwood
at 10:00 a.m.
I was off to the side
near the aisle when I saw him.
[door opens]
[door closes]
A guy so stunningly handsome
I thought at first
he was a movie star
or a model from GQ magazine.
He was tall.
He was undoubtedly
tan everywhere.
This boy aroused
something primal in me
that I'd never felt before.
I needed to be his friend.
I had to own him.
♪♪ Life's the same,
I'm moving in stereo ♪
The Warner Brothers logo
headed toward us
as the opening credits began
over aerial shots
of the family's Volkswagen
heading toward the Overlook.
He had to be older than me.
A UCLA student, maybe.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
I watched, mesmerized,
as this boy, this god,
disappeared from my sight line.
He noticed me
staring and glanced away,
but not before a lingering gaze
took me in,
and I fantasized that he
was interested in me too.
After the movie was over,
I was underwhelmed.
It was nothing like the book.
I felt cheated.
I walked into the lobby hoping
to find the boy,
but he wasn't anywhere.
I waited outside the theater,
but he wasn't there either.
What I didn't know then is that
I would actually
meet this boy again,
and his name
was Robert Mallory,
and that his arrival
at my high school
and into my life would coincide
with a season of horror
and murder
that would destroy us all.
"Redrum" over and over?
That's gonna haunt me
for the rest of my life.
Like, "redrum"? But...
[Bret] It has occurred to me
when talking about
what happened to us in 1981
that one thing
is evident: Kids today
have it fucking easy.
Sure,
being a teenager is hard now
because you have to deal
with puberty and sexuality
and online bullying,
but our generation had it
tougher because we had to
deal with serial killers.
Shadow.
[Bret] The early '80s
was the golden era
for serial killers.
All the legends
were on hunting sprees.
The Night Stalker,
the Hillside Strangler.
Shadow.
[Bret] As I prepared to
enter senior year...
Shadow.
...I had no idea
that my friends
and I would be hunted too
by perhaps the most
sadistic serial killer
of them all.
[phone ringing]
Hello.
[static buzzing]
[bubbling]
Hello.
[hangs up]
[Bret] This is our story.
Some of us
survived high school.
Some of us died.
But none of us
made it out alive.
[pills rattling]
- [man on TV] Darling.
- [screams]
[panting]
[phone ringing]
Hello.
[static buzzing]
[raspy breathing]
- Who is this?
- [line clicks]
- [wind blowing]
- [wind chime tinkles]
[dog barking]
[latch clicks]
[light bulb buzzing]
[dog barking]
[♪ eerie music plays]
[keys jingling]
[screaming]
[thudding]
[♪ "Vienna" ♪]
[Bret] I remember it was
a Sunday afternoon
before Labor Day,
and our senior year
was about to begin
on that Tuesday morning
of September 8th, 1981.
And I remember
that the Westridge Stables
were located on a bluff
above Malibu
where my girlfriend,
Deborah Schaffer, was boarding
her new horse, Spirit.
I was driving solo following
Susan Reynolds and Thom Wright
along Pacific Coast Highway.
♪♪ The feeling has gone
Only you and I ♪
♪♪ It means nothing to me ♪
Everything sped up
when you got your car
- at 16 in Los Angeles.
- ♪♪ Nothing to me ♪
You are now autonomous
in ways you hadn't been.
- You could take care
of yourself.
- ♪♪ Oh, Vienna ♪
You had become an adult.
- [whooping]
- [laughs]
[Bret]
This encouraged our parents
to work longer hours
or travel
with less restrictions,
leaving all of us behind
in beautiful empty houses
in Bel-Air and Beverly Hills
or Benedict Canyon,
and that was okay
with my friends and I.
We were the family.
We raised each other.
[laughing, chattering]
[Bret] We would usually
start our day by meeting
for lunch at Hamburger Hamlet,
where we'd crowd
into the red booths
for patty melts
after buying our tickets
for the next movie
at The Bruin.
Dinner was usually
at the food court
with breaks at the arcade
playing Space Invaders
and PAC-MAN.
Or look for new music
at Tower Records,
leafing through the paperbacks
at any number
of the large bookstores
that dotted the streets.
There were five or six in 1981.
That's the one.
[Bret] There are none now.
[laughing, chattering]
[Bret] I kept behind Thom's car
up the winding road
of the stables
where we parked
next to Deborah's
gleaming brand-new BMW.
We located Debbie
trotting Spirit by his reins.
[whoops] Rock it, Debbie.
[Bret] She was wearing
her riding attire.
There you are.
[Thom whooping]
[whinnies]
[Bret] I was aware of Spirit
being yet another example
of Debbie's carelessness
and privilege.
The cost of maintaining
and housing the animal
was astronomical,
but I don't think
she even cared.
In a way,
Debbie was an experiment.
I wasn't determined
to have a girlfriend
my senior year,
except if it had been
Susan Reynolds,
and yet Debbie
had become somewhat
inexplicably just that.
[♪ pop music playing]
♪♪ I, I, I wanna give you a kiss
I wanna... ♪
[Bret] We were at a party
at Anthony Matthews' house,
and she just started
making out with me
on a chaise lit by the pool.
I was stoned on a Quaalude.
She did a bump of coke.
It was midnight.
- [panting] Put it in.
I'm so wet.
- What?
And I was at a point
where I still tried to be
attracted to girls.
- There's people around.
- I want it. I want you, Bret.
[Bret] I surprised myself
and went with it.
Debbie always broke the rules.
By senior year, her hair was
a shade of platinum
inspired by Blondie.
If you were
in 11th or 12th grade,
makeup was minimally allowed,
but because Debbie was so rich,
she got away with murder
and wore her lipstick hot pink
- or blood red, always defiant.
- [school bell rings]
[laughing, whooping]
Look, Debbie, I'm you.
You guys, cut it out.
You're gonna spook the horses.
- Susan, please,
get off his back.
- [Susan] Okay.
This is
a $1 million horse from Arabia,
and you're gonna spook him
because you can't get off
Thom's back for five minutes.
You just scared all of them...
[Bret]
Thom Wright and Susan Reynolds
had been dating
since they were sophomores
and were now
the most popular people,
not only in our class,
but in the overall
student body.
It was obvious why.
Thom and Susan
were casually beautiful,
all-American,
and they both came
from wealthy families.
For about two years,
they were in love
until that fall of 1981,
when one of them wasn't.
Thom was always the ideal
of teen boy handsome,
and what was so alluring
about him was
that he didn't seem to care.
He had an intriguing blankness
that was attractive
and soothing.
He was the opposite of Susan,
school class president,
effortlessly
a straight-A student.
She kind of knew I was secretly
in love with her,
and I knew
everything about her.
When she got her period,
the problem with her mother,
every imaginary slight
and deprivation
she thought she was enduring...
- I love you.
- ... her crushes on classmates
before Thom.
She was to me
the most beautiful girl ever,
and to this very day,
the person I think I've loved
the most in my entire life.
Have you heard
from your parents?
This morning, still in France,
headed to Venice next week.
They're staying in Europe
indefinitely.
My mom said that
she still thinks
she wants to divorce him.
My dad said that
the trip has been good,
and they weren't coming home
until their marriage was
on solid ground again.
I hope it works out for them.
Sucks having divorced parents.
I miss my dad a lot.
My God, it's my dream,
all that freedom.
Who's cooking your food?
You don't cook.
[Bret] Rosa makes all my meals.
Gracias.
I just write all night
after she goes home
and do whatever I want.
Are you coming
to Debbie's house tonight?
It's the last party
of the summer.
Labor Day always makes me blue.
It's the end of something.
Oh, but this year is the
beginning of our senior year.
We're coming. Although, God,
Debbie's dad makes me
super uncomfortable.
- So goddamn gay.
- Thom!
Sorry, he is.
Last time I was there,
he asked me
if I wanted to take a Jacuzzi
with him in his bathroom,
not the one by the pool.
Pretended I got food poisoning
and left.
Yeah,
I get gay vibes from him too.
I don't think
Debbie's mom knows,
if you could believe it.
She likes the house, the trips,
going to the Oscars every year.
How many does he have again?
Oscars.
Two.
You know that book I'm writing?
I want him to buy it
and let me write the movie.
God, I hate coming here
every weekend just to watch her
ride this dumb horse.
- Why do we do this
to ourselves?
- Because we are nice people.
And this year,
we're gonna rule the school.
[all laughing]
- [Bret] Don't we already?
- [Susan] Help. [squeals]
[Bret] There's no helping you.
[♪ "Planet Earth" playing]
♪♪ Only came outside
To watch the night fall
With the rain ♪
♪♪ I heard you
Making patterns rhyme ♪
I don't understand.
I just think we need to cool it
for a while.
It's maybe gotten out of hand.
I agree.
Just remember,
we're good friends.
Always will be.
♪♪ Look now, look all around ♪
♪♪ There's no sign of life ♪
♪♪ Voices, another sound ♪
♪♪ Can you hear me now? ♪
♪♪ This is Planet Earth ♪
♪♪ You're looking at
Planet Earth ♪
♪♪ Bop, bop, bop, bop,
Bop, bop, bop, bop ♪
♪♪ This is Planet Earth ♪
♪♪ My head is stuck
On something precious ♪
♪♪ Let me know ♪
♪♪ If you're coming down
To land ♪
♪♪ Is there anybody... ♪
So,
what was that about with Ryan?
[groans]
Nothing.
We were just talking about
how excited we were to graduate
and get the hell out
of Los Angeles,
finally start our lives.
For sure, I'm going to school
on the East Coast,
not even a question.
♪♪ There's no sign of life ♪
♪♪ Voices, another sound ♪
Oh, my God.
Senior year
hasn't even started,
and I'm already exhausted.
- It's gonna take
so much planning.
- Like what?
Well, homecoming is in October,
and I have some rad ideas
for the class float.
And then of course,
Susan and Thom will be crowned
homecoming king and queen.
I don't wanna be
a homecoming queen
and wear some weird tiara.
Susan, I'll throw you a party
at the Beverly Hills Hotel,
and then we're doing
an after-party thing
on Dominic Thompson's
father's yacht, okay?
- [laughs]
- How much coke have you done?
A lot.
- Do you want some?
- Duh.
Oh, and I just booked
Tommy Tutone
for a private party
I'm throwing at
the Blue Bayou at Disneyland.
You know,
like a cool grad night thing?
We've all worked so hard.
We deserve a nice time.
We deserve nice things.
Blue Bayou,
the restaurant
inside the Pirates
of the Caribbean ride?
Yeah.
- That's awesome.
- [all laughing]
[♪ "This Town" playing]
[ice clinking]
[shaker rattling]
Four vodka sodas, please.
Oh, don't forget to invite
the new guy to Disney.
What?
There's a new guy
coming in on Tuesday.
A new addition
to our senior class.
That's strange.
You never get
a new kid senior year.
- What's his name?
- Um, Robert something.
Oh, Robert Mallory.
How do you know this?
Well, I was having a meeting
with Principal Croft
about my student body
presidential duties this year,
and he told me.
He lives in Century City
with his aunt
or stepmother or something.
- Well, that's weird.
- What's weird about it?
[chuckles]
If he lives in Century City,
he would have been eligible
to attend Beverly Hills High.
Why opt for our school?
Why drive all the way
to our school?
Well, he better be cute.
[all laughing]
Like you.
Meet me in my bedroom in ten?
I'm so horny.
[Thom] What did you mean
when you said
you didn't want to be
homecoming king and queen?
- Oh, God, Thom, it's so corny.
- Yeah, but, Susan, honey,
this is
what we've been waiting for
for four fucking years.
This is the coronation.
Everybody wants this.
Okay. For you,
I'll think about it.
♪♪ This town is our town ♪
♪♪ This town
It is so glamorous ♪
[Bret] That night in September
was one of the last nights
where there was no fear.
[indistinct chatter]
[♪ "Golden Brown" playing]
[Terry] You have to watch
The Godfather, Chinatown,
and The Story of O.
- You ever heard
of The Story of O?
- [boy] I have...
Bret.
- Oh. Hi, Mr. Schaffer.
- Call me Terry, buddy.
Sit down. There's something
I wanted to talk to you about.
You guys go off,
watch your movies,
tell me the details.
I wanna know your favorite.
Okay.
So... Debbie tells me
you're a writer,
or you want to be one?
Yes. Yeah,
I'm-I'm writing a novel.
Amazing.
Maybe you and I
should go talk about that
at lunch or something.
I'm always looking for
new young voices.
Our business needs that.
The movies need that.
I've always had my eye on you,
Bret.
[clicking]
Steven!
Steven, what the...
What in the fuck are you doing?
Debbie asked me
to take pictures of her guests.
She wants to make a scrapbook.
You know Debbie.
Bret and I
are going to go to lunch,
talk about his future.
Will you put it down
on the schedule, okay?
Le Dome.
Sure thing.
Yep, yep.
Thanks, Mr. Schaffer...
Terry.
Where is my husband?
Oh.
Hi, Mrs. Schaffer.
I asked you a question.
Where is my husband?
Have you seen him?
Yes,
he's-he's down by the pool.
Who was my husband with?
Uh...
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
Was he in the bushes,
sucking some young guy's dick?
Or did he proposition you?
[Steven]
Liz, have you been hitting
the wine coolers again?
You seem very tired.
Let's put you to bed.
You can go, Bret.
Okay.
Good night, Mrs. Schaffer.
Wait. Why?
You're not staying
for the movie?
I've already seen it.
Don't you walk away from me,
you little asshole.
Where are you going?
You gonna meet him upstairs?
I've known you
since you were ten years old.
- Don't you dare
walk away from me!
- Liz, enough.
I'm putting you to bed now.
You can take
your night-night pills.
[sobbing]
[clicks]
[♪ "Crimson and Clover"
playing]
♪♪ Now I don't hardly know her ♪
[phone ringing]
Hello?
[heavy breathing on phone]
Your mom is a psycho.
[Debbie chuckles]
Ignore her. I do.
Are you staying for the movie?
No, I've already seen
Continental Divide.
I wanna get home,
do some writing.
Unless you had another idea.
I thought you'd never ask.
♪♪ Yeah ♪
♪♪ My, my, such a sweet thing ♪
Wow. Babe.
You got muscular this summer.
Oh, you know, push-ups, swimming.
[Debbie chuckles]
Oh, I get a full striptease.
Mm-hmm. Mmm.
[Bret] Debbie always came fast.
Within minutes,
she could thrash out an orgasm.
[Debbie] Don't tease me.
[Bret] It took barely anything
to make her come,
and this was happening now.
- [Debbie squeals]
- [both laugh]
[Bret] You have to remember,
being gender fluid
was not something
that was allowed back then.
You had to be two people,
which was fucking exhausting,
and you had to compartmentalize.
My relationship with Debbie
was my public persona,
and my relationship
with Matt Kellner
was my secret, forbidden one.
Did you hear there's a new kid
starting school?
Isn't that weird?
Uh, why is that weird?
Who cares?
It's just weird
if someone enrolls
in senior year.
[Matt sighs]
Whatever.
That's all you ever say,
about anything.
"Whatever."
You smoke too much pot, Matt.
You're officially
the class stoner.
Did you know that?
Whatever. [chuckles]
Why don't you socialize,
Mattie?
Why didn't you come
to Debbie's party tonight?
Well, I told you.
I just wanted to, you know,
hang here and listen to the new
Elvis Costello album.
And get high, Matt. So tedious.
You're so smart,
but you don't let anybody in.
Well, we're friends, right?
Only when I drive over
and we fool around
in the shadows.
You have lost potential, Matt.
I'm worried about you.
[chuckles]
- I'm the most real person
in that school.
- [both laugh]
And you know it.
I think we should stop this.
Stop what?
This.
You don't need to say that.
Well, I wouldn't want you
to think that I don't care.
No, I don't think anything.
I don't think anything.
What happened to the aquarium?
Uh...
I don't know.
You don't know why
your aquarium is empty?
No, I came back the other day
and noticed
all the fish were gone.
- What are you looking for?
- My bong.
And here it is.
All right.
What happened to the water?
I don't know. My mom
usually takes care of it.
Do you think maybe
the cat got them?
[laughs]
You think Alex ate all my fish?
[Bret] I don't know.
Maybe we'll never know.
[Bret] Why?
Well, the cat's missing too.
- Not this time.
Yeah. What about last week?
What about last week?
Last week... Last week,
I wasn't feeling okay.
[laughs] Okay.
It's always an excuse, dude.
- Okay.
- Hey, check it out.
Gracias.
[weatherman]
It's gonna be a warm one for
the next week, I'm betting two.
You'll see here
we have a high of 82,
and the Santa Anas
are at least letting us
cool down to 71 at night.
Now, back to Jessica
for the morning report.
[Jessica] Some disturbing news
this morning in the Southland.
The body of a teenage girl
was found yesterday morning
on a tennis court
in Woodland Hills.
The body and identity
of the young woman
have not been released,
and police refused to comment
pending an investigation
into the homicide.
Viewers will remember that,
last summer,
the body of a missing girl,
Katherine Latchford,
was found
in a dumpster in Redlands.
That case remains unsolved,
and police decline to comment
at this time
whether the abductions
and murders are related.
[siren wailing]
What's wrong?
Did you see the mascot statue,
what someone did to it?
[Susan] Yes, I talked
to the principal about it.
It's just some stupid prank
by a kid at Harvard
or something.
Klonopin?
Sure.
[bell rings]
[laughter]
- Babe, what'd you get?
- Croissant and ham.
- I just wanna smell it,
honestly.
- [Bret chuckles]
You can have one.
Why does my stupid mother
always pack me pâté for lunch?
I just call it "pad thai."
She knows I'm dieting.
She's trying to sabotage me.
Pâté is not
on the Beverly Hills Diet.
- Want it?
- I do.
- Sure.
- Oh, Thom, you don't want that.
- You look great.
- [Thom] We can't always
get what we want.
I am not eating any more fat
for six weeks straight.
It just gets more round
if you continue to eat fat.
[Susan] You're gonna pass out.
To try and more angularize
the side profile.
[Susan] Of your boobs?
[Debbie] Can I smell a chip?
[Thom] You can take one.
[Debbie] I just wanna smell it.
[Susan]
She thinks that this works.
[Debbie] Have you noticed
that ever since I cut fat,
my tits from the side
are more angular?
- Look.
- Yes.
[Bret] You should know
I smelled him before I saw him.
It was cedar and sandalwood,
as if he had just walked
through a forest of citrus.
[Debbie]
Did you get a designer capsule?
- Oh, hi.
You must be Robert Mallory.
- You must be Susan.
- Principal Croft
showed me your picture.
- The one on his desk...
[Robert] From the yearbook.
I was just in
Principal Croft's office.
He told me
I should come say hi.
So, hi.
[Bret]
He wore black leather pants
like a second skin
with his school blazer.
I was rendered speechless.
I couldn't believe it.
It was him.
The magical, mystical boy I saw
at The Shining a year ago.
[Susan clears throat]
Hi. Bret.
Nice to meet you, Bret.
- You wanna join us?
- I'd love to.
[Debbie] Come on.
So, Robert,
where do you come from?
- So, I'm-I'm from Chicago
originally.
- Okay.
[Bret] Robert laid out
his background for us
as if it were a job interview
he needed to pass.
The last time he'd been in LA
for any sustained
length of time was
ten months ago when he came out
for the holidays
and stayed with his aunt.
Wait. So, why are you living
with your aunt now?
[Robert] Okay.
It's a funny story,
but I got kicked out
of my previous school
that I was at.
[Bret] Funny and smooth.
His parents were divorced.
His mother had then died
in a tragic accident.
His father wanted to send him
to a military academy,
but his aunt intervened,
suggesting Robert relocate to
Los Angeles and live with her,
and she would enroll him
somewhere for his last year
of high school.
Have we met before?
At The Whiskey
or The Odyssey or something?
I'm not much of a club guy.
I never forget a face.
[chuckles]
I don't really know
anyone in LA.
I don't go out much.
Did you not bring lunch?
I forgot.
I guess first day jitters, right?
[all chuckle]
Do you... Do you want half?
On one level,
Robert was intriguing enough
to make me forget
- about the griffin
streaked with gore.
- Sure, thank you.
He was one of the most
charming people I'd ever met.
The other thing I gleaned was
that he was a complete
and utter liar.
Oh, I know where I saw you.
Last summer,
did you see The Shining
at the Village Theatre
when it first came out?
No.
Are you sure?
I'm positive I saw you there.
- Really?
- Positive.
[chuckles]
Really? You're positive?
Why would you
remember me there?
Did I say something
to you or...
No, no,
you just left an impression.
I haven't seen that movie.
Well,
I'm almost positive I saw you.
In the theater. On a Saturday.
It wasn't me. [laughs]
[chuckles] Weird.
Very weird.
[bell rings]
- That was wacky.
- Hmm, saved by the bell.
- [Debbie] Nice to meet you.
- [Robert] Nice to meet you all.
[Susan laughs] Oh.
Bye, babe.
[Susan] Have you guys
heard of the water ride?
It was nice to meet you, Bret.
You too.
- Good afternoon.
- [students] Good afternoon!
Let's start the first assembly
of the year
by welcoming Senior President
Susan Reynolds.
Susan.
[cheering]
Stop, stop. Thank you.
Whoo!
- Hello, Griffins!
- [cheering]
I'm so proud of this girl.
[Susan] And hello
to my fellow senior class.
First of all, I just want
to say thank you to everyone
who voted for me
as your student body
class president.
We have a very exciting year
ahead of us.
Don't forget
our Thanksgiving fundraiser
following
the last football game
before the holiday.
Let's support our varsity team.
[cheering]
[indistinct chatter]
Yeah. I know.
[Bret] It became clear to me
after our second introduction
that Robert Mallory
was like a virus.
A new kind of insidious,
invading agent
who was here to destroy
the very cellular structure of
my friends, my school and me.
He was up to something.
And it was up to me to find out
exactly what that was.
[engine starts]
[♪ "Bad Boys Get Spanked"
playing]
[tires screech]
[increases volume]
♪♪ Don't you ever think about
The consequence? ♪
♪♪ Guys like you never do ♪
♪♪ That's the kind of stuff
That whores are made out of ♪
That floors are made out of ♪
♪♪ You know ♪
♪♪ Bad boys get spanked ♪
[tires screeching]
[revving]
♪♪ You don't listen,
Do you, asshole? ♪
♪♪ Don't be a punk
All your life ♪
♪♪ Someone's gonna
Sort you out ♪
♪♪ They'll try to make a man
Out of you ♪
♪♪ Now say, "Yes, sir,"
Say, "No, sir" ♪
♪♪ Say, "Yes, ma'am,"
Say, "No, ma'am" ♪
♪♪ You know, don't ya? ♪
♪♪ Bad boys get spanked ♪
Shit.
[tires screeching]
[horn blaring]
♪♪ Bad boys get spanked ♪
Shit.
♪♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪♪ Get spanked ♪
♪♪ Ooh ♪
♪♪ Come here, get spanked ♪
Fuck you.
♪♪ Get spanked ♪
[thud]
Fuck you!
♪♪ Come here ♪
♪♪ Get spanked ♪
[tires screeching]
Fuck you! Fuck you!
[♪ music stops]
[tires screeching in distance]
Oh, hey.
Hey.
That was you, right?
Following me?
I wasn't following you.
I was heading to the Galleria,
and I happened to be
behind you, I guess.
You were in the Porsche?
Yeah, that was me.
I was just fucking with you.
Hmm.
I don't like being followed.
Yeah?
You don't like being followed?
Yeah. Freaks me out.
What are you doing here
at the mall today?
Shopping
for some school clothes.
What brings you to the Galleria
on this Tuesday afternoon?
There's a lot of hot girls.
I was gonna see a movie,
but I realized
I've seen them all.
Which one? The Shining?
You sure you weren't there?
I know I saw you.
Dude, you gotta let it go.
It wasn't me.
Pretty sure I saw you, dude.
I haven't seen that movie.
What were you talking
to Matt Kellner about today?
Oh, yeah? You saw that?
You guys friends?
Is that innuendo?
He seems like
a very confused guy.
You know, the kind of guy
who could use a friend.
What? He's just very laid-back,
very easygoing. He's a pothead.
Interesting.
Is Thom
Susan Reynolds's boyfriend?
Um...
Yeah.
How long have they
been seeing each other?
How long have they been dating?
[Bret] About two years.
- So, it's serious.
- Very.
Why are you asking me this?
Because she's hot.
She's quite the little honey,
don't you think?
[Bret] At that point,
I couldn't breathe.
At that point,
I needed to get away from him.
Hey, Bret.
Yeah?
I've just figured something out
about you.
What have you figured out
about me?
When you talk to me,
you're really
talking to yourself, dude.
[Bret]
After the upsetting car chase
with Robert Mallory
on that sweltering and fateful
September afternoon,
I remember I went home
and popped on the local news.
...investigation
of a Valley Village girl
found brutally murdered
earlier today.
[Bret] What I learned that day
made my blood run cold.
The city had become
paralyzed with fear.
...might link to the murders
of at least two other
young women.
Questioned about
the suspect's identity,
investigators--
[Bret]
Margo Tyler had been missing
since June of that year
and her body was found
behind a local Tower Records.
She was his third victim.
There would be countless more.
The serial killer
hunting young people
was nicknamed
by investigating officers
as The Trawler.
Suddenly, the epidemic
of missing pets made sense.
He would use them
in a satanic way.
He trawled for victims
effortlessly, like a fisherman
casting a wide net.
Thus, the catchy nickname.
We'll continue to bring you
more as it comes in.
[newscaster]
Thanks, Jeff. At the moment,
things continue...
[TV turns off]
[phone ringing]
[man groaning]
Oh, my God. Oh, no.
Hello?
[groaning]
Oh, God. [screaming]
Hello?
[screaming continues]
Help me.
[sobbing]
[whispering]
Help me. Please, help me.
Hello?
[whimpering] Please, help me.
Oh, my God. No, no.
- Hello?
- Help! Help!
[♪ rock music playing]